## Kerri Miller

### Software Engineer

kerrizor@kerrizor.com

## Summary

I am an experienced developer and group leader with years of programming, design, and small team management experience. I am in favor of pair programming, technical book clubs, speaking at conferences, and teaching. Frequently asked to fill the role of technical project manager and team lead, I have managed a variety of each on scales ranging from corner store web sites to large national brands at "Internet scale". I am often in the role of bridging the gap between hard demands of technology and the soft desires of business and art.

#### I believe in:

- + communication
- + making mistakes
- + asking questions
- + pairing and collaboration
- + refactoring towards happiness
- + measuring success

# Experience

### Lead Software Engineer at Northwest Independent Ruby Development (NIRD LLC)

August 2013 - Present (3 years 4 months)

#### Speaker at conferences, meetups, and user groups

2009 - Present (7 years)

Recent talks include:

<sup>&</sup>quot;Crescent Wrenches and Socket Sets: Building a Rational Debugging Toolset" - CondeConfLA 2016

<sup>&</sup>quot;How To Gamble Everything On An Algorithm" - MoonConf 2016

<sup>&</sup>quot;We're Bad At Interviewing (And How To Fix It)" (RailsConf 2015)

<sup>&</sup>quot;Hidden Secrets of Your Database" (Ancient City Ruby 2015)

<sup>&</sup>quot;Concurrency for !Dummies" (Scottish Ruby Conf 2014, Nickel City Ruby 2014)

<sup>&</sup>quot;How To Interview And Why" (Burlington Ruby Conf)

<sup>&</sup>quot;Harry Potter and The Legacy Code Base" (Big Ruby Conf 2014, Ruby on Ales 2014)

<sup>&</sup>quot;Gambling for Rubyists" (Cascadia Ruby Conf 2013, CodeMash 2014)

<sup>&</sup>quot;Failure for Fun and Profit" (RubyConf 2012, Ruby Midwest 2013, Scottish Ruby Conf 2013)

<sup>&</sup>quot;Code Metrics: Measure All The Things!" (Ruby on Ales, 2012, Ruby Nation 2013)

\_\_\_

Recent Lightning Talks:

"FizzBuzz'ing your way to fame and fortune"

"Squirtgun - a quick overview of a node.js event logging service"

#### Application Engineer at GitHub

January 2016 - September 2016 (9 months)

#### Instructor at RailsBridge

August 2011 - August 2016 (5 years 1 month)

RailsBridge is an organization that works to increase diversity in tech by conducting free 1.5 day programming education intensive workshops for women. I teach attendees, who range from zero experience to currently employed IT professionals, conduct office hours and attend meetups to allow for follow-up discussions and mentoring, contribute to curriculum, and participate in the organization of individual events.

#### Lead Software Engineer at LivingSocial

May 2014 - November 2015 (1 year 7 months)

### Lead Instructor at Ada Developers Academy

September 2013 - May 2014 (9 months)

Ada Developers Academy (ADA) is an intensive software developer training school for women. It combines six months of classroom instruction in cutting-edge web technologies with up to six month of apprenticeship at a Puget Sound-area tech business.

In the 24 week intensive class, students are immersed in software development and learn the most up-to-date web skills from leading regional and national experts. Afterward, during a six month apprenticeship, students learn what it's like to be part of a software team delivering production code for real applications.

http://adadevelopersacademy.org

#### Application Team Lead/Sr SDE at BlueBox

February 2012 - July 2013 (1 year 6 months)

I lead a small team focused on both curation of several large-scale existing legacy applications as well as greenfield development on new product and service offerings that allow customers to create and manage flexible and specialized solutions.

#### Engineering Manager/Lead Developer at Contour, Inc.

October 2007 - February 2012 (4 years 5 months)

<sup>&</sup>quot;How to wash your hands, redux"

I was lead developer in the effort to rapidly launch a new consumer electronics helmet camera, desktop application, and video sharing site, originally built upon the Drupal CMS platform and Amazon.com's EC2/S3 service.

In 2009, I led the team tasked with migrating the technical platforms to Ruby, and coordinated internal and external design and development teams to launch the desktop and mobile applications used by the Contour cameras on time and under budget.

In 2011, I was named Engineering Manager/Lead Developer and took responsibility for delivering desktop, firmware, and backend improvements that led to Contour being listed in Inc, Magazine's Top 500 fastest growing startups for 3 years, including #7 fastest growing startup in 2011.

### Lead Developer at BroadbandSports.com

August 2005 - October 2007 (2 years 3 months)

I designed and delivered a full-stack website featuring video transcoding, archiving, and user-contributed content, with users allowed to tag video clips with non-heirarchical folksonomy terms, focused primarily at the "extreme" and participatory sports audience, built on Drupal CMS. Worked with the Drupal community to contribute to and provide ongoing maintenance for a pair of popular Drupal taxonomy modules.

#### Sr Web Development Engineer at Amazon.com

March 2000 - March 2005 (5 years 1 month)

I was an early member of Amazon.com's Personalization & Discovery group, using aggregated customer data in automated advertising and merchandising features. I worked on high-profile (and high-revenue) features such as Item Similarities, Top Sellers/New Releases, Page You Made, ListMania, search result automation, automated content and delivery systems, and targeted email campaigns. I was also a contributing member on multiple I18N launches, the Target.com launch, and several speculative UI/UX projects. During my tenure, I developed using Mason, PHP, Ruby, and Perl in a Linux-based, self-administrated distributed development environment.

# Volunteer Experience

### Instructor at RailsBridge

RailsBridge is an organization that works to increase diversity in tech by conducting free 1.5 day programming education intensive workshops for women.

#### Organizer at Open Source & Feelings 2015

October 2014 - Present

Open Source & Feelings is a two-day, single-track conference centered around the intersection between open source software and the humanities, and how we communicate and engage with the communities we're a part

of. It is about deliberative crafting of OSS culture into what we want it to be, about developing strategies, skills, and solutions in order work as a community.

### Curriculum Development and Organization at Ada Developers Academy

August 2013 - Present

## **Projects**

#### FizzBuzz.io

November 2011 to Present

Members:Kerri Miller

FizzBuzz.io is a demonstration project for the idea of breakable toys, a topic which I have spoken on at technical conferences, and employ as a teaching tool when directly teaching or mentoring junior developers.

#### Turbulence

Members:Kerri Miller

Turbulence is a static analysis tool for graphing code complexity versus its churn rate, in order to discover potential areas where bugs are most likely to be introduced.

#### **ContourPLUS**

April 2011 to Present

Members: Kerri Miller, Dirk Haije, Jeff Huisman, Richard Mander, Kathleen McVey, PMP, Christopher G Alviar, Chris Doyle, Jonathan Dughi

## Languages

Ruby

**SQL** 

Perl

CSS

**Javascript** 

**PHP** 

node.js

# Organizations

### RailsBridge

Teacher, TA

January 2011 to Present

#### **DevChix**

January 2010 to Present

## Skills & Expertise

Ruby

**Software Development** 

**Ruby on Rails** 

**Web Development** 

Perl

Git

**Scalability** 

**Agile Methodologies** 

**Test Driven Development** 

**Web Applications** 

**Cross-functional Team Leadership** 

**Object Oriented Design** 

**Software Engineering** 

**General Awesomeness** 

**Software Design** 

**Programming** 

**Open Source** 

**REST** 

**Web Services** 

**Apache** 

**Bash** 

**User Interface Design** 

**Pair Programming** 

**Android** 

**XML** 

**CSS** 

**Amazon Web Services (AWS)** 

Node.js

**PostgreSQL** 

**Agile Project Management** 

**AJAX** 

**User Experience** 

**Curriculum Design** 

Kanban

Scrum

**Distributed Systems** 

MongoDB

**Subversion** 

**jQuery** 

**HTML 5** 

**Mentoring** 

**JavaScript** 

**Mobile Applications** 

**HTML** 

**MySQL** 

HTML5

(#°#°### ###

Twitter capsule reviews

## **Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)**

## Education

# Cornish College of the Arts

Bachelor of the Arts, Performance Production, 2004 - 2005

## **Goddard College**

BA, Performance Production, 1993 - 1996

## Interests

lighting designer, puppeteer, cooking,poker,hiking,Vespas, glassworking

## Kerri Miller

## Software Engineer

kerrizor@kerrizor.com



## 6 people have recommended Kerri

"Kerri is one of the nicest people that I have worked with in the tech industry. Her calmness and levelheadedness is unflappable and this enables her to be a very effective developer, even in some of the most stressful and unrelenting situations. Kerri writes solid code and has a solid personality to back it up, an award winning combination."

### — Spike Graham, worked with Kerri at BlueBox

"Kerri is pretty amazing: a poet programmer, a forward-looking renaissance thought leader, with the right amount of structured discipline to deliver elegant results. It is a real pleasure working with Kerri. - Brian Johnson"

### — Brian Johnson, worked with Kerri at BlueBox

"Kerri is undoubtedly a good leader to her team, but I observed her being a good leader to everybody who could help improve her team's products. Her dedication to quality and her support to anybody willing to chip in made her a personal resource of mine as I spent my downtime developing my fledgling software development skills. One episode is particularly memorable: I was assigned a job role which the ticketing system didn't quite support. The same day I mentioned this fact, Kerri appeared at my desk to discuss a feature set which would improve my workflow. I wasn't at Blue Box long enough to see its inception, unfortunately, but Kerri's proactive dedication to the users of her team's product definitely stood out to me. Kerri has remained a resource to me since my departure from Blue Box. In that light I have noted her dedication to her craft and her general cool-person-ness."

### — Chad Cassady, worked indirectly for Kerri at BlueBox

"Kerri is extremely hard working, loyal, responsible, and committed to excellence. Kerri works best in a collaborative environment where she may play devil's advocate in one discussion, and argue passionately for a better approach another conversation. She is always exploring new advances both within her field, and in a wide variety of fascinating interests outside the office. Kerri is as committed to a good business result as a good engineering product. Kerri is the developer working weekends even when not in crunch mode, the voice in the room pointing out the Emperor's new clothes, and the team member who always finds an appropriately

silly website to boost spirits when times are low. Special recommendation for Kerri's status reports which are the most entertaining status reports ever."

#### — **Blunt Jackson**, managed Kerri at Contour, Inc.

"Kerri has earned my complete trust over and over again across all aspects of software development, and I have watched her earn everyone else's trust as well. Kerri is always available for a conversation about what's on my mind, from HR stuff to architectural planning to code reviews to just shooting the breeze. I know she will do her best to solve any problems I'm having (with the utmost discretion where applicable), and advocate for my ideas across the company. Or, politely and positively suggest that I might want to reconsider some of those ideas (which, of course, I should). She chooses her words carefully and with empathy, but isn't going to sugarcoat or gloss over something that isn't right. Kerri consciously maintains relationships with other teams outside of our normal job-based interactions. I think this is what lets her get ahead of any inchoate problems and keep our team distractions to a minimum. People know her and know she's on point for web-related issues, so she is able to distill and focus the needs of the organization before they reach our backlog. On the technical side, Kerri fearlessly attacks our weak spots, be it caching HTML fragments or tracing through gnarly backend systems. She's constantly checking our service metrics, optimizing slow queries, and thinking about ways to make our codebase faster and cleaner - often taking advantage of new technologies to reduce our workload. Kerri trusts us as developers to look out for the good of the company and the quality of our work without micromanaging. She leads by example; we can't help but emulate her integrity and commitment. In a nutshell, Kerri has cultivated one of the best team environments in which I've had the pleasure of working."

### — Chris Doyle, reported to Kerri at Contour, Inc.

"I was fortunate to work with Kerri for nearly three years in a young start up environment. It takes a very special/borderline crack personality type to thrive in such a workplace, and Kerri nailed it. Her dedication to building our web platforms from scratch is something I deeply admire, and she did it all with great integrity and creative oomph."

— Julie Carroll, worked with Kerri at Contour, Inc.

Contact Kerri on LinkedIn